

jordanyu1992@gmail.com 778.700.5528 BC, Canada linkedin.com/in/jordanu92

# SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Technical backend expert delivering reliable infrastructure.

Ex-Google software developer with ~8 years in all levels of backend software development. Direct experience with cloud infrastructure (AWS, GCP), database management (SQL, NoSQL), web protocols and data exchange (REST/RPC/JSON/Protobufs). Known as an excellent communicator and collaborative team member working with technical and non-technical staff to relay and document features across the organization.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### COURSE HERO Vancouver, BC

2021-2023

Senior Backend Software Engineer - Payments Infrastructure

- Migration of legacy subscription platform onto 3rd party system (Recurly)
- Silent migration affecting 2+M users and 1k+ daily payments
- Automated process to ingest 500K+ transactions for financial revenue recognition
- Tech: PHP, Symfony, AWS, K8S, Golang, Recurly, Paypal, Braintree

#### GOOGLE Mountain View, CA, USA

2015-2020

Senior Software Engineer - Dialogflow/Google Assistant

2018-2020

- Developed backend services for custom natural language processing (NLP) chatbots
- Developed Java APIs for Designtime service processing 1M+ model edits per day
- Silent migration from GCP to Borg, 99% uptime through monitoring, daily regression/AB tests
- Tech: Java, Spanner, Bigtable, GCP, RPC

Software Engineer, Tools and Infrastructure - AdSpam

2015-2018

- Regression, performance tests, build and release infra for Ads spam filtering pipelines.
- Maintained large scale (10+ services) on-demand testing infra for online spam pipeline.
- Mentored 3 interns, providing guidance, outlining project scope, weekly 1:1 meetings
- Google 20% Internal diff tool (Bagua) ran 1K+ daily regressions tests for 100's teams Implemented parallel processing pipeline (c++), web frontend UI components (Python/JS).
- Tech: C++, Python, JS, Golang, Bazel, Spanner, Bigtable, Cloud(borg)

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

	Professional (2-3+ years)	Beginner (~1year)	Personal (0-5 years)
Languages	Python, Go, Java, PHP	C/C++, Javascript	Rust (3mo)
Web	Symfony, JSON	HTML/CSS,JS React,Angular	Node, OAuth
Infrastructure	GCP, SQL Relational (MySQL, Spanner) NoSQL (Bigtable)	Kubernetes, AWS	
Tools	Git, VSCode, Slack	New Relic, Datadog,Bazel	Vim, Android Studio, Linux, Docker, Unity3D
Misc	Braintree, Paypal, Recurly		OpenGL, Graphics, SDL Spine

Internships

A Thinking Ape Vancouver, BC, Software Engineer Intern - Unity3d game developer prototyping a multiplayer RPG game.	2014
IBM Victoria, BC Web Software Developer - Client/Server web applications for LotusNotes	2014
SAFE SOFTWARE Surrey, BC Build and Release Intern - Manual and automated testing of geospatial software suite	2013
LATITUDE GEOGRAPHICS Victoria, BC Quality Assurance Intern - Manual regression, integration testing of geospatial software	2012

## Education

Bachelors of Software Engineering, University of Victoria, Grad. 2015

- Computer Networks, Computer Architecture, Operating Systems, Databases, Graphics
- Data Structure and Algorithms, Algorithms for Hard Problems, Programming Languages
- Software Development Methods (Design Patterns, Models, Requirements, Quality Engineering)
- Discrete Mathematics, Statistics, Time Signals and Systems

# **Personal Projects**

## **Arknights Chibi Bot**

- https://akchibibot.stymphalian.top/
- A twitch bot and browser source overlay to show chibis walking on your stream.
- Viewers issue text commands in chat to change the sprite, do different animations, etc
- **Tech:** Golang, JS/HTML/CSS, Twitch API, Spine, PostgreSQL, Docker

## Personal AI/ML Library

- <a href="https://github.com/Stymphalian/saiml">https://github.com/Stymphalian/saiml</a>
- From scratch implementation of AI/ML algorithms and data structures with numpy.
- Some features include convolutions, transformers, diffusion and autograd.
- **Tech:** Python, numpy, cypy/cuda